{"tossups": [{"question": "Barbara Jordan and Zell Miller gave keynote addresses during party national conventions held in this specific location. In 1982, Sun Myung Moon held the first Blessing Ceremony of the Unification Church outside of Korea in this location, conducting a mass wedding in which 2,500 people were married. The Hulu Theater at this location is currently slated for demolition as part of plans to expand nearby Penn Station. For ten points, identify this New York City concert hall and sporting venue named for the fourth president.", "answer": "<b> Madison Square Garden</b> (or<b> MSG</b>; prompt on partial answers; prompt on New York City before read)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This period of time provides the nickname of the queen Elizabeth Stuart, the eldest daughter of James I. During this period of time in 1947, Manny Shinwell was vilified by the British public for failing to maintain adequate supplies of coal. The headline \u201cCrisis? What crisis?\u201d ran during an instance of strife named after this period of time, during which James Callaghan\u2019s government instituted pay caps and lost an election to the Conservative Party under Margaret Thatcher. For ten points, what period \u201cof discontent\u201d names a blizzard-filled season in 1979?", "answer": "<b> winter</b> (accept<b> Winter</b> Queen; accept<b> Winter</b> of Discontent)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man won a mayoral race on the ticket of the Family Party, which began his lifelong feud with the leader of the rival Amalgamators, James Buchanan. This man cast a tie breaking vote to pass the Walker Tariff, effectively destroying his reputation in his home state of Pennsylvania, though he was popular as vice president for supporting the annexation of Texas. For ten points, name this politician who was James Polk\u2019s running mate and who probably is not the namesake of a Texas city founded in the 1840s.", "answer": "George M.<b> Dallas</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Some of Jean Sibelius\u2019s final works were written for this institution, including an opus 113 suite and an arrangement of<em> Finlandia</em> with new lyrics. Three basset horns are included in the score for a piece of\u201cfuneral music\u201d written for this organization. A member of this organization, Emmanuel Schikaneder, wrote the libretto for an opera featuring the Queen of the Night and the bird-catcher Papageno. The composer of<em> The Magic Flute</em>, Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, was a member of the Beneficience Lodge of, for ten points, what Enlightenment-inspired fraternal organization?", "answer": "Free<b>mason</b>s (accept anything related to<b> Masonic</b> lodge(s), etc.) Page 2", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "Simon Metcalfe massacred inhabitants of this kingdom in Olowalu before his assistants John Young and Isaac Davis went to work for its king. Men and women were forbidden from eating together by this kingdom\u2019s<em> kapu</em> system of taboos. This kingdom\u2019s founder protected citizens during wartime with the Law of the Splintered Paddle. Lorrin Thurston helped write this kingdom\u2019s Bayonet Constitution, and he later overthrew its Queen Liliuokalani. For ten points, name this kingdom that was unified after the conquest of Oahu.", "answer": "Kingdom of<b> Hawaii</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Catherine Green may have fixed design flaws in an invention by this man, but was given no public credit. Fones McCarthy created an updated version of an invention by this man that would handle long-staple resources. Despite no experience and the recent loss of his factory to a fire, this man agreed to make 10,000 muskets for Congress. The boils and lint were separated by a device created by, for ten points, what proponent of interchangeable parts and inventor of the cotton gin?", "answer": "Eli<b> Whitney</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In the eighth of this poem\u2019s nine sections, \u201cThe Spinning-Wheel,\u201d a woman becomes angry when her fianc\u00b4ee likens her to Bertha the Beautiful Spinner. A woman in this poem asks \u201cWhy don\u2019t you speak for yourself\u201d when a man delivers his best friend\u2019s proposal of marriage to her. This poem imagines a love triangle between John Alden, Priscilla Mullens, and its title character. For ten points, name this Henry Longfellow poem about a romance in Plymouth Colony.", "answer": "The<b> Courtship of Miles Standish</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Poetry"}, {"question": "This war included the Battle of Norfolk, a tank battle fought the day after the Battle of 73 Easting. The health effects of this conflict were investigated in the Riegle Report, which concluded that soldiers were exposed to chemical weapons. A stretch of road in this conflict was named the \u201cHighway of Death,\u201das many soldiers were killed trying to retreat to the Euphrates. Norman Schwarzkopf led coalition troops in, for ten points, what early 1990\u2019s war in response to an invasion of Kuwait?", "answer": "First (Persian)<b> Gulf</b> War (accept<b> First Iraq</b> War; accept Operation<b> Desert Storm</b>; prompt on Operation Desert Shield) Page 3", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "At a battle in this body of water, the<em> Mainz</em> was sunk by a fleet under Reginald Tyrwhitt. That first naval battle of the First World War was held in a bight of this body of water. In this body of water, Admiral Rozhestvensky failed to offer lifeboats after attacking a trawler fleet that was mistakenly thought to be part of the Japanese Navy. In a 1916 battle in this body of water, John Jellicoe defeated a German fleet. The Dogger Bank incident took place in, for ten points, what sea bordering the United Kingdom and Scandinavia?", "answer": "<b> North</b> Sea", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Basil Hart claimed that this man was the first \u201cmodern general\u201d in history. The forces of Leonidas Polk were defeated in a campaign led by this man that ended with the capture of Meridian. This man accepted the surrender of Joseph Johnston\u2019s forces at Bennett Place in North Carolina. This general, who allegedly came up with the saying \u201cwar is hell,\u201d sent a telegram offering 25,000 bales of cotton as part of a Christmas present after a campaign that was meant to \u201cmake Georgia howl.\u201d For ten points, name this Union general who led a March to the Sea.", "answer": "William Tecumseh<b> Sherman</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this American intelligence agency whose secrets were leaked by Edward Snowden.", "answer": "<b> National Security Agency</b> (accept<b> NSA</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "As a result of this event, the Cameronians suppressed the Dundee Rebellion at the Battle of Dunkeld. Members of the MacDonald clan were killed in the Glencoe Massacre for failing to swear loyalty to a king installed in this event; that king won the Battle of the Boyne and was a stadtholder from the House of Orange. The 1689 English Bill of Rights was passed after this event, which removed the Catholic James II. For ten points, name this bloodless revolution in which William III and Mary II became rulers of England.", "answer": "<b> Glorious</b> Revolution (accept<b> Bloodless</b> Revolution before \u201cbloodless\u201d is mentioned; accept <b>English</b> Revolution of<b> 1688</b>; prompt on descriptive answers related to the overthrow of James II before mentioned and/or the installation of William and Mary before \u201cWilliam\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Adam Lemp founded a brewery in this city, where he introduced Lager Beer. Marguerite Scypion filed one of the first \u201cfreedom suits\u201d in this city. During the Civil War, Nathaniel Lyon captured a state militia at Camp Jackson that was planning to attack this city\u2019s</b> <b>arsenal. Auguste (+)</b> <b>Chouteau helped found this city, where Minoru Yamasaki built the</b> <b>Pruitt-Igoe housing project. In this city, one of the first bridges that utilized (*)</b> caissons was built by James Eads to cross the Mississippi River. For ten points, name this city where Eero Saarinen built the Gateway Arch.", "answer": "<b> St. Louis</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>During this war, the \u201cRed Prince\u201d led a charge of several hundred freed Chinese slaves with Jose Francisco Gana. The winner of this war demanded the Tarapaca Province at the Lackawanna Conference. During this war, captain (+) Miguel Grau sank the</b><em><b> Esmerelda</b></em><b> at the Battle of Iquique, but lost his ironclad</b><em><b> Huascar</b></em><b> at the Battle of Angamos. This war, which began over a tax dispute near (*)</b> Antofagasta, was ended by the Treaty of Ancon. For ten points, name this South American war that pitted Peru and Bolivia against Chile over mineral reserves in the late 19th century.", "answer": "War of the<b> Pacific</b> (or Guerra del<b> Pacifico</b>; accept<b> Saltpeter</b> War)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Prince Xerxes defeated this man\u2019s forces at the Battle of Thannuris in the Iberian War. This man fought over the region of Lazica with Khosrau the Great, with whom he signed the Treaty of Eternal Peace. During this man\u2019s reign, the (+) Blues and Greens began riots</b> <b>over chariot races in the Nika Revolt. This Emperor\u2019s generals Narses and (*)</b> Belisarius reconquered Italy from the Ostrogoths. For ten points, Theodora married which Byzantine Emperor who built the Hagia Sophia and ordered the creation of a namesake law code?", "answer": "<b> Justinian the Great</b> (accept<b> Justinian I</b>; prompt on Justinian) Page 10", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b>\u2018Anas ibn Malik noted that some of the fallen at the Battle of \u2018Uhud had broken this practice; he noted that Allah revealed that no blame would be attached if \u201cthey fear Allah and believe and do righteous deeds.\u201d The caliph Umar criticized \u201cthe Sword of God,\u201dKhalid ibn al-Walid, for breaking this practice while (+) taking baths. The \u201cjoy of all Rus\u201d[roose] would have violated this practice, and so Vladimir the Great chose not to (*)</b> convert his people to a certain religion.<em> Khamr</em> is the subject of, for ten points, what religious proscription that Jahangir often broke, as he was fond of brandy?", "answer": "<b> Islam</b>ic<b> ban</b> on consuming<b> alcohol</b> (accept<b> Khamr</b> before mentioned; accept equivalents for each of the three underlined parts, including any specific type of alcohol; prompt on partial answers, like\u201cban on booze\u201d)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "<b>This book states that \u201cthat which is not \u2018body\u2019 is no part of the universe,\u201d supporting a corporeal view of God. In a feud with its author, bishop John Bramhall published a tract about the \u201cCatching of\u201d this book. This book, which was begun while its author taught (+) mathematics to a young Charles II in Paris, calls ignorance of scripture the \u201cKingdom of (*) </b> Darkness.\u201d This book\u2019s first section, \u201cOf Man,\u201d argues that the state of nature is characterized by the war of all against all. For ten points, name this book that argues for strong monarchies by Thomas Hobbes.", "answer": "<b> Leviathan</b> or, The Matter, Forme and Power of a Commonwealth Ecclesiastical and Civil", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Henrik Bergh defended this client, who was accused of ordering the execution of Gunnar Eilifsen. This man, who was also accused of smuggling rubles with Frederik Prytz, worked</b> <b>with Fridtjof Nansen to alleviate the 1921 (+)</b> <b>Russian famine. This leader worked with</b> <b>the Nazi Reichskommissar Josef Terboven. After King Haakon VII fled, this Nasjonal (*) </b>Samling leader became head of his country with the support of the Nazis. For ten points, name this collaborationist Norwegian leader whose name is now synonymous with the word \u201ctraitor.\u201d", "answer": "Vidkun<b> Quisling</b> ([qviz-ling], but be lenient) Page 11", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>William Malet was one of the 15 \u201cproven companions\u201d of the victor of this battle. Henry of Huntington describes how men on the winning side were trampled after</b> <b>charging into a feature later called the (+)</b> <b>\u201cEvil Ditch.\u201d Orderic Vitalis is a major</b> <b>source for information on this battle, whose losing commander positioned his troops on Senlac Hill. Bishop Odo commissioned an (*)</b> embroidery that ends with depictions of this battle. The Bayeux Tapestry depicts, for ten points, what victory for William the Conqueror in 1066?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Hastings </b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}